# Fedor Lisin

### ML Engineer

Moscow. Russia RU

☑ theo.lisin@gmail.com ☐ +7 (965) 004-85-95

It took me around two years to realise that I like programming in general and data science in particular. Since taking the Yandex classes, well-written, readable code has become my intention. My current focus is creating products that benefit or facilitate the lives of people, not just reviewers.

### SKILLS

# ML and Data Science Intermediate Sklearn PyTorch statistics FastAPI Pydantic ORM SQLAlchemy ML frameworks Github Actions Gitlab Pipelines

### Common

VSC	Gitlab		Github		
Reviewing		L	ir	nux	

### **WORK EXPERIENCE (3)**

Research Engineer at Huawei 2024 - Current

Research on ways to improve Wi-Fi quality of service (QoS) and solve optical tasks.

- Developed model for traffic delay prediction and improved simulation of the GPON system using NS3 library (Classinc ML, C++)
- Set up an environment to simplify and accelerate the work of the team: S3 storage for raw data, MLFlow for experiment logging (Docker)
- Researched symbolic regression methods for tasks involving optical physics models (RL, FunSearch, MCTS)

### Python Developer at Supervisely OÜ

2023 - 2023

Create a new app on the Supervisely platform for model serving and training

- Developed new SOTA model training and serving applications for the Supervisely ecosystem (PIPs, YOLO, MMDetection, MixFormer etc.)
- Enhanced capabilities of the SDK: support for point and object tracking with NN models and linear interpolation
- Found and fixed several critical bugs in the cache functionality, which was causing applications to crash (Pytest, Asyncio)

### Junior Data Scientist at OCRV, Russian Railways affiliated company

2021 - 2022

Developed different models from scratch for tabular data and time series, upgraded the current data infrastructure, supervised the students' self-study pet projects.

- Train delay investigation system: improving data infrastructure with PySpark, time to create the final dataset was at least cut in half. (Catboost, PySpark, ClickHouse)
- EEG motor imaginary classification: examining the primary methods for getting, classifying, and filtering EEG data, as well as developing experimental data collection methods. (ICA, SSP, WPD)
- Recommendation system for ticket sales: assisted interns with GIT and Django, helping to implement baseline solutions. (Git, Conda, Django)

### PROJECTS (2)

### Voice emotion recognition using Wav2Vec

2021 - 2021

☐ https://github.com/TheoLisin/Emotion\_Recognition\_with\_Wav2Vec

Wav2Vec transformers telegram-api

Speech emotion recognition model based on Wav2Vec with telegam-bot user interface.

- Trained 8-class classifier on RAVDESS dataset using Wav2Vec pre-trained model.
- Developed a Telegram bot to gather more data and test the model on Russian speech.

## Monotone Hurwitz numbers in genus zero

2019 - 2020

mathematical physics graph theory

University-authored bachelor's thesis

### EDUCATION (2)

Bachelor Theoretical Physics at St. Petersburg Academic University of RAS

2016 - 2020

Data Science, MLOps at MADE Data Academy

2022 - 2023

### CERTIFICATES

### Machine learning | course authored by Stanford University

Coursera, Stanford University

2020-07-25

### Machine Learning Engineer

MADE Data Academy

2023-07

https://data.vk.company/curriculum/certificates/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/

### LANGUAGES

English Intermediate Russian

Native Speaker

INTERESTS

Games

Airplanes

Traveling

PPL